Guide to the Student Activism at Yale University Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Student activism at Yale University collection
1984-1991
RU 351
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.25
(4 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, notes, memoranda, newsclippings, and flyers, maintained by Christopher Lowe and Ann Braude documenting student activism, sexual harassment, affirmative action, and women's groups at Yale. Records concerning the following groups and events are included: the Yale Student Labor Support Group; the Coalition Against Apartheid; T. A. Solidarity (TAS) and the Graduate Employees and Students Organization (GESO); the 1984 and 1988 labor strikes at Yale; and the student anti-war movement against the Gulf War.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 41 (YRG 41), Material documenting Yale student life.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, notes, memoranda, newsclippings, and flyers, maintained by Christopher Lowe and Ann Braude documenting student activism, sexual harassment, affirmative action, and women's groups at Yale. Records concerning the following groups and events are included: the Yale Student Labor Support Group; the Coalition Against Apartheid; T. A. Solidarity (TAS) and the Graduate Employees and Students Organization (GESO); the 1984 and 1988 labor strikes at Yale; and the student anti-war movement against the Gulf War.
Graduate Students -- Political activity; Labor disputes; Labor unions; Persian Gulf War, 1991 -- Protest movements; Student movements; Student protesters; Students -- Political activity; Graduate Employees and Students Organization (GESO); T. A. Solidarity; Yale University -- Graduate Students -- Political activity
- Materials documenting student activism at Yale maintained by Christopher Lowe, circa 1984-1991; Accession 1994-A-089
  - 1984 strike
    - Student support groups, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - History Department, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Local 34, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Student library sit-in, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Administration (student and teaching fellow oriented), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Political fliers, notes on activism and labor history, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1987-1988 Negotiations
    - Local 34 job survey, student action for 1988 contract, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - American Studies, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Graduate Organizing Committee; Holiday Inn union contract negotiations, contract, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Labor Support Group
      - Member lists, circa 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Fundraising committee, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Meeting minutes, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Origins, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Meeting agendas, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Events, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Posters, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 16 - 17)
      - Leaflet on negotiations, circa 1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - HRAF, 217, other unions, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Fliers, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Agendas and membership list, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Contracts, working notes, drafts of white paper, circa 1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - White paper notes, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Notes on Local 35 history, circa 1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Clippings, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Faculty responses, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Other groups, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Union material, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Administration, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Articles on Yale unions, circa 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Strike propaganda and miscellany, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Report of the Joint Committee on Job Descriptions and Classifications, 1987 July 1 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Coalition Against Apartheid
    - Divestment Movement history, circa 1984 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Notes, 1985 fall (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Educational materials, 1985 fall (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Yale and South Africa, 1986 spring (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Organization and actions, 1986 spring (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Educational materials, 1986 spring (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Related material, 1986 spring (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Yale administration, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Lobbying Connecticut state legislature, 1986 spring (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Shanty Town action, 1986 spring (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986 spring (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Divestment/South Africa, 1986 fall (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Unified List of United States Companies with Investments or Loans in South Africa and Namibia, 1985 June (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Clippings; Complaint Against the Dean of Yale College and the Yale College Executive Committee, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Clippings, drafts of letters, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Self-educational material, circa 1985 (Box 1, Folder 48 - 50)
    - New Haven Free South Africa/Connecticut Anti-Apartheid Coalition, circa 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Minutes, lists, and notes, circa 1985 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Background information on divestment, circa 1985 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Notes, member lists, fliers, circa 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 54 - 55)
  - Anti-war, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Yale-New Haven anti-war, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - T. A. Solidarity
    - 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 58 - 59)
    - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Graduate Empoyees and Students Organization (GESO)
    - Information packet, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Notes, drafts, etc., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Notes, fliers, articles, posters, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 63 - 64)
- Materials documenting student activism at Yale maintained by Ann Braude, 1976-1985; Accession 2008-A-158
  - Affirmative action/equal opportunity, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Graduate-Professional Student Senate, Inc., 1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Graduate program Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Sexual harassment, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Sexual harassment grievance committee procedures, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Strike by Local 34
    - Administration statements, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Class action suit form, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Clippings, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Contact lists, circa 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Faculty memos and open letters, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - General information, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Graduate and Professional Support Group, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Hardship fund, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Heidi Hartmann nomination, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Letter to the editor, Yale Alumni Magazine, 1984 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Letters to Eleanor Holmes Norton, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Letters to president A. Barlett Giamatti, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Local 34 brochures, newsletters, and flyers, circa 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - New Haven Board of Aldermen resolution, 1984 October 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - News releases, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Notes and drafts, circa 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Open letters to students and parents, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Petitions, circa 1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - The Picket Line (student publication), 1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Posters and flyers, circa 1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Songs, circa 1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Transcript of conversation with A. Bartlett Giamatti, circa 1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Yale Alumni Fund 1983-1984 Annual Report (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Yale Graduate Women's Association, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Yale Religious Studies Women, 1976-1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Yale Women's Action Committee, circa 1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Yale Women's Center, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Yale Women's Study Program, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)